ANUJ PARIKH

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Atlanta, GA

657-257-8267

parikhanuj31@gmail.com

SUMMARY —

4+ years of valuable experience in designing web applications as a Front-End developer/ Software Developer in various domains. Understanding of different SDLC methodologies such as Agile and Waterfall. Ability to build Single Page Application (SPA) using Framework such as React.JS and Node.JS framework. Proficient in developing front-end systems with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, jQuery, Ajax, Json, Bootstrap and JavaScript frameworks such as ReactJS. Knowledge of using various tools and IDEs for development and design like Eclipse, Visual Studio Code and Microsoft Visual Studio. Proficiency in application servers such as IBM WebSphere and WebLogic. Working knowledge of databases like PostgreSQL, MongoDB and MySQL. Good knowledge of Version Control Systems like Git and MS Visio.

EDUCATION —

Masters in Computer Science

University of New Haven, West Haven, Connecticut

Bachelor in Computer Engineering

Gujarat Technological University, India

EXPERIENCE

Jan 2022 – Oct 2023 Software Developer • Calloquy, PBC, Georgia

- Developed and maintained web applications using PHP Laravel, React, HTML, CSS, MySQL, PostgreSQL, AWS, JavaScript and Livewire.
- Collaborated closely with UX/UI teams to create visually appealing and intuitive user interfaces.
- Implemented RESTful APIs for seamless data interaction between frontend and backend systems.
- Leveraged PDFTron to implement document editing capabilities and Jitsi to provide high quality, scalable video conferences.
- Conducted unit testing with PHPUnit and Jest to ensure code quality and reliability.
- Integrated third-party APIs to extend application functionality and data retrieval.
- Optimized application performance by minimizing load times and enhancing user experiences.
- Actively participated in Agile development processes, including sprint planning and daily stand-up meetings.

Aug 2021 - Jan 2022

Programmer in Insurance Systems • Vsquare Infotech Inc., NJ

- Working with various software methodologies such as SDLC and Agile.
- Developing front-end application and components using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, react for the login and manage module.
- Developing a cross-browser application which is a mobilefirst web application forsharing the real-time location by using Node.JS, React.JS and API.
- Working on React.JS directives, Controllers, Filters, Services, Templets, Events, and Injectors.
- Working proficiently in various IDEs including Visual Studio Code and Eclipse.
- Translate designs into high-quality code and write application interface code viaJavaScript following React.JS workflows.

KEY SKILLS —

Methodology:

SDLC, Agile, Waterfall

Frameworks/Libraries:

React.js, Node.js, Express.js, Laravel, Livewire

IDE's:

Visual Studio Code, NetBeans, Eclipse

Technologies:

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Typescript, jQuery,JSON, Ajax, Bootstrap, PHP, Jitsi, XML

Testing Tools:

Gulp, Grunt, Jest, Laravel Testing

Web Server:

WebSocket, Apache Tomcat, Web Sphere

Databases:

PostgreSQL, MongoDB, MySQL, AWS

Version Control Tools:

Git, SVN

Operating Systems:

Windows, Linux, MacOS

Jan 2017 – July 2019 Front End Developer • BrainByte Infotech, India

- Involved in Waterfall Methodology to help manage and organize a team of developers with regular code review sessions.
- Built Rich Prototypes and Applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax,JSON, ReactJS, and Bootstrap with MySQL database.
- Crafted custom React hook components across different modules employing ReactJS, Redux and Material UI.
- Worked with Grunt and Gulp as an associate to Node.JS to establish the connectivity between database and client.
- Developed and configured MySQL Database tables including Sequences, Functions, Procedures and Table constraints.
- Developed and Deployed the Application on Eclipse and Web Sphere Server.
- Wrote services to store data and retrieve user data from MongoDB for theapplication.
- Used Git for version control and Source Tree to facilitate it and Jenkins for continuous integration.

LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS

- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner (AWS)
- Front-End Web Development with React (Coursera)
- Introduction to HTML5 (Coursera)
- Python Course: Build 10 real world Applications (Udemy)
- Python Programming (Udemy)